Guide to the William R. George family papers, 1750-1989.
George, William R. family papers, 1750-1989.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
William R. George family papers, 1750-1989.
800
George family.
83.1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, manuscripts, diaries, money, bound periodicals, blueprints, notebooks, photographs, sketches, clippings, wax recordings, transcripts
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection contains extensive correspondence and other materials concerning William R. George and the founding of the George Junior Republic, the evolution of the Republic and its part in educational reform in the early twentieth century; and the establishment of other Junior Republics in the United States
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
William Reuben George, a social welfare leader, founded the George Junior Republic in 1895 in Freeville, New York as a means of moving boys and girls from the slums into a rural environment. The Junior Republic, a community reflecting the principles of youthful self-government, was founded upon the maxim "Nothing Without Labor." With assistance from his wife Esther Ide Brewster, George developed a community consisting of a farm, blacksmith and carpentry shops, laundry, bakery, general store, jail, and other elements of the larger society which were intended to complement citizens' academic endeavors. By 1898, the first of several institutions based on the Republic's principles was founded in Redington, Pa., and by 1908, the National Association of Junior Republics was formed with George as Executive National Director.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection contains extensive correspondence and other materials concerning William R. George and the founding of the George Junior Republic. The collection also contains material which documents the evolution of the Republic and its part in educational reform in the early twentieth century; the establishment of other Junior Republics in the United States; and George's ideas about the Child Labor Amendment, communism, socialism, pacifism, and the welfare state. Also included is extensive correspondence, 1807-1985 of George and the George family, including thousands of letters from former citizens, benefactors, and persons interested in social reform; George Junior Republic Association records, unpublished articles by George, minutes of councils, and annotated notes; manuscripts (ca. 1909-68) with book drafts, drafts for articles and speeches, and material about the Phalanx movement. Also, diaries (1881-1962), and other volumes, including memobooks, account books, steno notebooks, address books, guestbooks, and scrapbooks. Although a fire destroyed many of the Republic's work records, the collection still includes some record books (1895-1923).
Extensive published material which was printed at or concerns the George Junior Republic (1895-1985), and three books by William R. George, THE JUNIOR REPUBLIC, CITIZENS MADE AND REMADE (with Lyman Beecher Stowe), and THE ADULT MINOR are also included, as well as blueprints, plans, and certificates, museum items, photographs, albums, and sketches (1889-1955) depicting the early days of the Republic, family and friends of William R. George, citizens, ex-citizens, helpers, and officials of the Republic; genealogies of the Georges and related families; newspaper and magazine clippings (1809-1985); unidentified wax recordings; transcripts (1965) of five interviews done by Jack Holl and Frances Keefe; papers relating to Gerrit Smith Miller; and papers kept by Malcolm Freeborn (1930-85) concerning many committees and councils of the Junior Republic, and Freeborn's work with senior citizens and with the Tompkins County Youth Court.
Correspondents include Andrew Carnegie, Alexander Forbes, Willard E. Hotchkiss, Leonard S. Levin, Gerrit Smith Miller, Susan Dixwell Miller, William C. Orton, Theodore Roosevelt, Jacob Gould Schurman, Lyman Beecher Stowe, Sao-Ke Alfred Sze, Richard Welling, and many others.
SUBJECTS
Names:
George family.; Carnegie, Andrew, 1835-1919.; Forbes, Alexander, 1835-; Freeborn, Edith George.; Freeborn, Malcolm J.; George, Esther Brewster, 1872-1962.; George, William R. (William Reuben), 1866-1936.; George, William R. (William Reuben), 1866-1936. Junior Republic.; George, William R. (William Reuben), 1866-1936. Citizens made and remade.; George, William R. (William Reuben), 1866-1936. Adult minor.; Holl, Jack.; Hotchkiss, Willard E. (Willard Eugene), b. 1874.; Keefe, Frances.; Levin, Leonard S.; Miller, Gerrit S. (Gerrit Smith), 1869-1956.; Miller, Susan Dixwell.; Orton, William C.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Schurman, Jacob Gould, 1854-1942.; Stowe, Lyman Beecher, 1880-1963.; Sze, Sao-Ke Alfred, 1877-1958.; Welling, Richard, 1858-1946.; George Junior Republic Association.; League for the Promotion of Civic and Economic Responsibility.; National Association of Junior Republics.; Tompkins County (N.Y.) Youth Court.
Subjects:
Aged.; Anti-communist movements.; Child labor.; Child labor--Law and Legislation.; Children--Institutional care.; Discipline of children.; Education.; Juvenile delinquency.; Reformatories.; Social problems.; Youth--Employment.; Youth--Employment--Law and legislation.; Youth--Political activity.; Social reformers.
Places:
Freeville (N.Y.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Account books.; Blueprints.; Genealogies.; Manuscripts.; Negatives.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Sketches.; Speeches.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Series I. Correspondence
Boxes 1-54
Series II. Manuscripts
Boxes 55-59
Series III. Bound Volumes - Manuscripts
Boxes 60-87
Series IV. Miscellaneous
Box 88
Series V. Printed Material
Boxes 89-111
Series VI. Blueprints, Plans, and Certificates
Located in map-cases
Series VII. Museum Items
Boxes 112-117
George Family Museum Items
George Junior Republic Currency
George Junior Republic Musuem Items
Series VIII. Photographs, Photo Albums, Negatives, Printed Photographs, and Sketches
Boxes 118-137
Photographs of William R. George
Photographs related to William R. George
William R. George Family Photographs
Photographs of Friends of William R. George
Fresh Air Days Photographs (George Junior Republic)
Early Days Photographs (George Junior Republic)
Photographs - 1900-1905 (George Junior Republic)
Photographs - 1906-1919 (George Junior Republic)
George Junior Republic Activities and Group Photographs
Photographs of Republic Buildings and Grounds
Photographs of Republic Employees and Officials
Photographs of Other Republics
Photographs of George Junior Republic Ex-citizens
Oversize and Miscellaneous Photographs
Tintypes, Glass Plates, Negatives, and Miscellaneous
Negatives
Miscellaneous Rolled Photographs
Photograph Albums
Printed Photographs and Sketches
Series IX. Genealogy
Boxes 138-140
Series X. Gerrit Smith Miller Papers
Boxes 140-141
Series XI. Clippings
Boxes 142-144
Series XII. Wax Recordings
Boxes 145-150
Series XIII. Oral History Transcripts
Series XIV. Malcolm J. Freeborn Papers
Boxes 151-
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - George, Thomas; Tyson, John; Toan, William; Toan, Rachel; George, Joel, 1807-1896 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Apprenticeship agreement; Promissory note. (Annotations.)
  - Baker, Mary; Baker, Andrew; Tyson, Esther; George, John F., 1859-1864 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Marriage certificates; National Guard certificates and records; Church roll book. (Annotations.)
  - Civil War inventories, lists, Jan. - Mar.1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Civil War equipages, invoices; John F. George and Eleanor Baker marriage certificate. (Annotations.), May - Dec.1865 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bergen, John E.; Graham, M.J., 1866-69 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Civil War equipages, invoices, lists. (Annotations.)
  - Reddy, W.; Tyson, Esther; George, John F.; Baker, R.T., 1871-80 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Missionary Society certificate; Masonic directory; Preacher's license; Temperance Union card. (Annotations.)
  - Family correspondence. (Annotations.), 1881 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Family correspondence. (Annotations.), 1882 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - George, John F., 1883-84 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Family correspondence; Preacher's License. (Annotations.)
  - George, Esther B., 1885-87 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Family correspondence; National Guard certificates; Preacher's license; Diary/notebook. (Annotations.)
  - George, Eleanor B., 1888-91 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Family correspondence; Newspaper clipping; Church certificate. (Annotations.)
  - Tyler, B.B., 1892-94 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Exhorter's license; Preacher's license; Fresh Air Camp list of helpers, regulations; Obituary; Family correspondence; Verses. (Annotations.)
  - Wright, Lloyd B.; Schell, R. Montgomery; Orton, William Clifford; Osborn, J.H., 1895 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    William R. George diary extracts; George Junior Republic Association notes, papers, regulations, donation slips and lists, solicitation forms, subscription blank; Newspaper clipping. (Annotations.)
  - Drafts of the report of the General Superintendent. (Annotations.), 1896-99 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - George Junior Republic list of helpers; "Farm Scheme"; "Appreciated Currency"; Constitution of the George Junior Republic, 1896-97 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Miller, Gerrit Smith; Weed, Nellie S.; Hotchkiss, Willard E., 1896-99 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Report of the Business Manager; "The Publishing House," a description of the curriculum and teaching at George Junior Republic; Parents/Guardians' agreement; lists. (Annotations.)
  - Orton, William Clifford; Curtis, M.E., Jan.Jun1896 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Orton, William Clifford; George, Esther B.; Miller, Elizabeth M. Smith; Miller, Gerrit Smith, Jul. - Dec.1896 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Wedding place cards and gift list. (Annotations.)
  - Anderson, Arthur; Dapping, William O.; Orton, William Clifford, Jan. - Mar.1897 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    List of helpers; "Report of the George Junior Republic Criminal Court Judge"; Parent correspondence; George Junior Republic administration.
  - Osborne, Thomas Mott; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Orton, William Clifford; Cooper, M.W.; Callahan, Charles F.; Commons, J.R., Apr. - Jun.1897 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Letters from citizens; Letters from parents. (Annotations.)
  - Colon, H.S.; Commons, J.R.; Cady, Edwin Welling, Jul. - Sep.1897 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    List of winter citizens; McClure's Magazine account of George Junior Republic; Letters from parents; "Waldorf Hotel Contract." (Annotations.)
  - George, Esther B.; Commons, J.R.; Cooper, M.W.; Osborne, Thomas Mott; Cooper, Ella; Smith, Jacob G.; Markham, Edwin; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Westervelt, James, Oct. - Dec.1897 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Draft of amendments to Constitution; Letters from parents; "President's Letter"; "President's Message"; Letters from parents; "Girl Citizens." (Annotations.)
  - King, Moses; Osborne, Thomas Mott, 1896-1897 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    George Junior Republic incorporation papers; list of members of Advisory Council. (Annotations.)
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell; Callahan, Charles F., Jan. - Mar.1898 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Letters from parents; Letters from citizens; List of citizens; "Bank Report." (Annotations.)
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell; Milbury, Arthur W.; Osborne, Thomas Mott; Wright, Lloyd B.; Cooke, Bella; Wendell, E.J., Apr. - Jun. 1898 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    The Industrial Christian Alliance; Church directory; Letters from parents. (Annotations.)
  - Osborne, Thomas Mott; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Willard, S.D., Jul. 1898 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Letters from parents.
  - Osborne, Thomas Mott; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Crum, S.F.; Miller, Gerrit Smith, Aug. 1898 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Letters from parents. (Annotations.)
  - Osborne, Thomas Mott; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Wright, Lloyd B.; Maguire, A.C.; Carter, Nellie R., Sept. 1898 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    (Annotations.)
  - Dapping, William O.; Miller, Elizabeth M. Smith; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Osborne, Thomas Mott; Wright, Lloyd B.; Osborne, John H., Oct. 1898 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Conklin, Mark; Wright, Lloyd B.; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Cockburn, Frank M.; Osborne, Thomas Mott; Osborne, John H., Nov. 1898 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Letters from parents; Library record. (Annotations.)
  - Osborne, Thomas Mott; Offer, George E.; Price, James M.; Wright, Lloyd B.; Conley, James, Dec. 1898 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    "Who's Who in America"; List of rule-breakers; "Notes" concerning operation of and developments at George Junior Republic.
  - Cooper, E.C.; Osborne, Thomas Mott; Wright, Lloyd B.; Cooper, M.W., Jan. - Jun.1898 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Letter from William R. George to Thomas Mott Osborne; Citizens' pledge to specified actions and behavior; Letters from parents.
  - Cooper, Ella; Wright, Lloyd B.; Cooper, M.W.; Hirsch, Frank; Osborne, Thomas Mott; Price, James M.; Cooper, E.C., Jul. - Dec.1898 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Letters from parents; Draft of legal document; "Contract for Dining Rooms"; Notes copied from London newspapers concerning James Tyson; Drafts of letters dictated by William R. George; Lecture notes. (Annotations.)
  - Osborne, Thomas Mott; White, Edith H.; Agnew, A.G.; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Kirk, Eleanor; Cooper, M.W., Jan. 1899 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Draft of letter from William R. George to Thomas Mott Osborne. (Annotations.)
  - Cooper, M.W.; Commons, J.R.; Carter, Nellie R.; Osborne, Thomas Mott, Feb. 1899 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Cooke, Bella; Cooper, M.W.; Osborne, Thomas Mott; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Carter, Nellie R., Mar. 1899 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Notes concerning the George Junior Republic Agricultural Association (Annotations.)
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell; Price, James M.; Bannon, Mamie, Apr. - May1899 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell; Price, James M.; Bannon, Mamie; Cuthbert, Eddie; David, Leo; Seidell, William C.; Balderston, John L., Jun. 1899 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Announcement to "girls especially" of penalties for setting beds on fire. (Annotations.)
  - Bannon, Mamie; Seidell, William C.; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Cuthbert, Eddie, Jul. 1899 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell; Bannon, Mamie; Price, James M.; Young, Leonard; Markham, Edwin; David, Amy C.; Price, Sarah L., Aug. - Sep.1899 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Manuscript of the poem "The Song of the Muse of Labor" by Edwin Markham. (Annotations.)
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell; Feinberg, Richard; Bannon, Mamie; David, Amy C.; Bartol, Leah; Nelson, Maud E., Oct. - Dec.1899 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Bannon, Mamie; Cooper, M.W.; Davis, Amy C.; Brady, Anna Marie; Carpenter, Josephine E.; Cooper, D.B.; Commons, J.R.; Miller, Susan Dixwell. (Annotations.), 1899 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Ostrander, Sarah; Young, Leonard; Bannon, Mamie; Nelson, Maud E., 1899 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Letters from citizens; Statement of citizen Frank Adams; "Daddy's Prophecy," signed by several citizens.
  - Bannon, Mamie; Smith, Jacob G.; MacGregor, Margaret C.K., Jan. - Feb.1900 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Letters from citizens. (Annotations.)
  - Bannon, Mamie; Bartol, Leah; Nelson, Maud E.; Bohrmann, Charles C., Mar. - Apr.1900 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Bannon, Mamie; Davis, Amy C.; Smith, Jacob G.; Bohrmann, Charles C., May - Jun.1900 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Quit-Claim Deed for Susan Dixwell Miller; Annotated wedding invitation; Letters from citizens.
  - MacGregor, Margaret C.K.; Bohrmann, Charles C.; Bannon, Mamie; Oliver, Adele E., Jul. - Nov.1900 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Report to State Board of Charities; Annotated wedding invitation.
  - Bohrmann, Charles C.; Bannon, Mamie; Bartol, Leah, Dec. 1900 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Smith, Jacob G., 1900 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    "Care and Treatment of Children," by William R. George; "Honor Among Thieves," by Lyman Beecher Stowe; Paper dictated by William R. George. (Annotations.)
  - "The Meaning of G.J.R." by William G. Beach; Telegram from Theodore Roosevelt. (Annotations.), 1900 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - King, Edward M.; Beach, William G.; Bartol, Leah; Roosevelt, Theodore; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Osborne, Thomas Mott; Bohrmann, Charles C., Jan. - Jul.1901 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    Inaugural Address of Edward King as Fifth President of George Junior Republic, and letters of 1954 and 1936 to and from Edward King and William R. George; Correspondence concerning the birth, illness, and death of George Tyson George; Letters from citizens. (Annotations.)
  - Osborne, Thomas Mott; Miller, Susan Dixwell, Aug. - Oct.1901 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Citizen discharge slips; Page signed by citizens of sympathy for death of George Tyson George.
  - Greenleaf, Arthur P.; Richardson, Eugene A.; Feldmann, Edmund; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Bulkley, L. Duncan, Nov. - Dec.1901 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    Confession of Eugene A. Richardson. (Annotations)
  - (Box 3)
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell., 1901 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    Telegrams and letters concerning the birth and death of George Tyson George.
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell; Bartol, Leah; McCoy, George E.; Seidell, William C., Jan. - Aug.1902 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    George Junior Republic expenditures card.
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell; Bannon, Mamie, Sept. - Dec.1902 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    George Junior Republic Administration; Poll list; List of George Junior Republic administrators. (Annotations.)
  - Bartol, Leah; Thurston, Hattie; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Smith, Jacob G.; Beach, William G., 1903 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    List of graduates and citizens and their current status; List of various important dates in George Junior Republic history. (Annotations.)
  - Osborne, Thomas Mott, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Pages dictated by William R. George; George Junior Republic Law Case #56.
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell, Jan. - Mar.1904 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell; Howe, Archibald; Osborne, Thomas Mott; Miller, Hervey E.; Albertson, Henry H.; Albertson, Amy; Miller, Gerrit Smith, Apr. - Dec.1904 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Lists of citizens entering, present, discharged; Notes of an address by William R. George. (Annotations.)
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell; Seidell, William C.; George, Amazilla Douglas; Brewster, George Tyson; Parker, Grace E.J.; Albertson, Amy, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Wafer production list; Poem by Frederick Palmer; Picture of Miller Memorial library; "Glimpse of the George Junior Republic" by Hocking, Agnes Boyle O'Reilly.
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell; Miller, Gerrit Smith; Selden, Joseph H.; Stone, J. Sumner, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Agreement between George Junior Republic and Tompkins County; Treasury Department agreement allowance to John E. Bergen; Orchard trees.
  - Fowler, Margaret B.; Beecher, George A.; Cabot, Philip; Miller, Susan Dixwell, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    List of boarders and guests at Howland House; Agreement between George Junior Republic and Tompkins County. (Annotations.)
  - Lindsey, Ben B.; Miller, Gerrit Smith; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Beach, William G., May - Aug.1907 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Miller, Susan Dixwell; Treadwell, George Curtis; Fowler, Margaret B.; Miller, Frank A., Sept. - Oct.1907 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Fowler, Margaret B.; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Wilbur, Curtis D.; Stoddart, Evelyn L.; Hoffman, W.R., Nov. - Dec.1907 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Election results; Agreement between George Junior Republic and Tompkins County; Personal correspondence; Postcards concerning the Georges' trip west; Malcolm Freeborn birth certificate.
  - Stoddart, Evelyn L.; Storer, Elizabeth D.; Miller, Gerrit Smith; Best, Lucy S.; Rauh, Bertha F. (Annotations.), Jan. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Helm, Nathan Wilbur; Stoddart, Evelyn L., Feb. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Testimonial to William R. George from citizens; Letter from William R. George. (Annotations.)
  - Tone, William; Lindsey, Ben B.; Thacher, Sherman; King, Fred A.; Helm, Nathan Wilbur; Stoddart, Evelyn L.; Fowler, Margaret B., Mar. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    International Juvenile Court Society; California George Junior Republic.
  - Lucas, John G.; Cady, Harry O.; Baldwin, Juliet, Apr. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Committee of One Hundred; American Health League certificate. (Annotations.)
  - Lyle, Chester A.; Baldwin, Juliet; Lindsey, Ben B.; Hutchins, John, Apr. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    International Juvenile Court Society; Letter from parents; George Junior Republic, Litchfield Branch; Treasury Department allowance to John E. Bergen; California George Junior Republic.
  - Beach, William G.; Levin, Leonard S., May 1908 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    International Juvenile Court Society.
  - Bedford, Nathaniel L.; Levin, Leonard S.; Cady, Harry O., May 1908 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    California George Junior Republic.
  - Levin, Leonard S.; Stoddart, Evelyn L.; George, John F.; George, Eleanor Baker, Jun. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Edith George birth certificate; Letters from citizens.
  - Levin, Leonard S.; Stoddart, Evelyn L.; Hughes, Charles E.; Miller, Susan Dixwell; Bedford, Nathaniel L., Jun. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Baldwin, Juliet; Stoddart, Bessie D.; Stoddart, Evelyn L.; Clift, Mary F.; Bedford, Nathaniel L.; Levin, Leonard S.; Hurley, John W., Jun. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Letters from citizens; California George Junior Republic. (Annotations.)
  - Butt, Emily; McClellan, William Fred; Stoddart, Evelyn L.; Offenheimer, Nannie; Bedford, Nathaniel L., Jul. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Fowler, Margaret B.; Cady, Minnie; Milliken, O.J.; Clift, Mary F.; Bedford, Nathaniel L.; Bartol, Leah; Cady, Harry O.; Stoddart, Evelyn L., Jul. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    California George Junior Republic; Letters from citizens.
  - Cady, Minnie; Beach, William G.; Thacher, Eliza Blake; Eberle, Warren C.; Gute, William A., Aug. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    Committee of One Hundred; "The Republic Star."
  - Baldwin, Juliet; Bowen, Robert A.; LeRoy, Harris G.; Offenheimer, Nannie; Livingston, Bessie, Sept. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - George, Orra Kelsey; Bowen, Robert A.; Heineman, Charlotte C.; Lindsey, Ben B., Oct. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    Carter Junior Republic.
  - Porter, Katherine; Campbell, Mary A.; Thompson, Frances H.; Baker, Leslie W.; Eberle, Warren C.; Robinson, W.C.; Stoddart, Evelyn L., Oct. 1908 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    National Junior Republic. (Annotations.)
  - Robinson, W.C.; Dwight, John W.; Hughes, Charles E.; Balch, Anne L.; Campbell, Mary A.; Bowen, Robert A.; Baldwin, Juliet; Hotchkiss, Willard E.; Lindsey, Ben B.; Livingston, Bessie; Baker, Leslie W.; Miller, Susan Dixwell, Nov. 1908 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    National Junior Republic; George Family genealogy.
  - Offenheimer, Nannie; Baldwin, Juliet; White, Andrew D.; Fowler, Margaret B.; Porter, Katherine, Dec. 1908 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Letters from citizens; Juvenile Protective Association; National Association of Junior Republics. (Annotations)
  - Lyle, Chester A.; Bell, Bertha Sage; DeWitt, W.A., 1908 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Constitution and By-Laws of the National Association of Junior Republics; Typescript by William R. George concerning the early history of the George Junior Republic; Report for the National Association of Junior Republics by William R. George; Drafts of letters dictated by William R. George; Constitution of the George Junior Republic Security and Loan Company. (Annotations.)
  - Bedford, Nathaniel L., 1908 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    "Underlying Principles of the George Junior Republic" by William R. George.
  - Fowler, Margaret B., 1908-09 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Drafts of letters dictated by William R. George. (Annotations.)
  - Smith, Jacob G.; Levin, Leonard S., Jan. 1909 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    California George Junior Republic; Agreement between George Junior Republic and Tompkins County; Letters from citizens.
  - Hurley, John W.; Thacher, Sherman; Bowen, Robert A.; Gearhart, Wilbur Fisk; Porter, Katherine; Michelsen, P.S., Jan. 1909 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Porter, Katherine; Livingston, Bessie; Bowen, Robert A., Feb. 1909 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Letters from citizens.